Guide to the Thomas Merton Center Records, 1962-2009 AIS.1982.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Fifth Deposit (2009), 1962-2009; V.
  - Administrative Files, 1980-2009; 1.
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 51)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Amy Goodman, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 52)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Angela Davis, 2006 (Box 51, Folder 53)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Archbishop Hunthausen, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 54)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Cindy Sheehan, 2007 (Box 51, Folder 55)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Don Dellums, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Malik Rahim, 2008 (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Molly Rush, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Richard Hughes, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Thomas Merton Award Dinner, Father Roy Bourgeois, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Thomas Merton Center Annual Report, 2000 (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Thomas Merton Center Annual Reports, 2003-2006 (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Thomas Merton Center Antiwar Rally, January 26, 2003 (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Thomas Merton Center Board Meetings, 1984-1987 (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Thomas Merton Center Budget Grants, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 65)
    - Thomas Merton Center Community Report, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 66)
    - Thomas Merton Center Donation Letters, 1984-1986 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Thomas Merton Center ED Applications/Interview Notes, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Thomas Merton Center Events (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Thomas Merton Center Finances, 1990-1994 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Merton Center Financial Records, 1983-1985 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Thomas Merton Center Fundraising--"Birdie Blue," City Theatre, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Thomas Merton Center Fundraising/Training, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Thomas Merton Center Giving Tree and Thrift Shop Open House, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Thomas Merton Center Internship Opportunities, University of Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Thomas Merton Center Job Descriptions, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Thomas Merton Center Mission Statement and Goals, 1990s (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Thomas Merton Center New People Fundraiser (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Thomas Merton Center Pappy Youth Program, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Merton Center Project, New Voices Pittsburgh, 2009 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Thomas Merton Center Projects, 2007-2008 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Thomas Merton Center Public Relations, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Alice and Staughton Lynd, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Anthony Padavano, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, James Forest, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Jim Thuline, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Jim Wallis, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Marie Dennis, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Phil Berrigan, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Richard Rohr, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Thomas Merton Center Retreat, Sylvia Rosell, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Thomas Merton Center Twentieth Anniversary Retreat, Jim Forest, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Thomas Merton Center Twentieth Anniversary, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Thomas Merton Center Volunteer Information, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Thomas Merton Center Volunteer List, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Thomas Merton Center Volunteer Thank You List, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Thomas Merton Center Volunteer/Internship Information and Forms (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - Thomas Merton Center Work-study Partnership with Chatham College, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Volunteer Award Applications, 1995-1997 (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Volunteer List, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - Volunteerism--TMC set-up (Box 52, Folder 35)
  - Subject Files, 1962-2008; 2.
    These records in the subject files subseries span the Center's existence from 1962 to 2008. These files document the different regional and international peace and social justice issues the Thomas Merton Center brought awareness to, or organized against through projects and protests in an effort to bring about social change. Several folders are devoted to Pittsburgh-area projects that dealt with issues of racism, war, apartheid, hunger, the rights of women and children, and labor. Also included is a run of the Center's newspaper, The New People, which highlighted Center events, featured social justice articles, and acted as a source of information for other activists and like minded organizations on actions, campaigns, and events.
    - Alternative Christmas, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Anti-Apartheid, South Africa, 1984 (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Arts Organizing Against Racism, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - CEASE Project/Information, ca. 2003 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Chiapas Project, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Citizens Budget Campaign, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Concert, Mike Stout, 2000 (Box 52, Folder 42)
    - Day of Reflection, Gregory Norbet, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 43)
    - Death Penalty, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - Death Penalty Protest, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Dick Gregory, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - The Effects of Nuclear War on the Pittsburgh Area, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 47)
    - Euromissile Action Days, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 48)
    - Evaluations, Urban League, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 49)
    - Fair Shake Festival, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 50)
    - Fair Shake Festival, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 51-52)
    - Fair Trade, 2007 (Box 52, Folder 53)
    - Fast For Life, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 54-55)
    - F.B.I. Surveillance, Thomas Merton Center, 1980s (Box 52, Folder 56-58)
    - Festive Fundraiser, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Foot Washing Ceremony, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Freedom Seder, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Gandhi Event, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Global Town Meeting Radio Broadcast, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Good Neighbors Volunteers, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Green Peace Correspondence (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Greenham Common Woman Tour, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Heinz Central America Phonathon and Meeting, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Hiroshima Fifty Years Events, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Human Rights Workshop, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "I am a Man Fundraiser", 1997 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Ida B. Wells Event, City Theatre, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - In Sisterhood Project, 2008 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Ina Braden Center for Volunteer Programs, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Indochina Peace Campaign, Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Iraq Petition, 1998 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Iraq Vigil, February 26, 1998 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Iraq Voices in the Wilderness, 1998 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Jim Wallis Talk, 2000 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Jubilee Conference, 1984-1986 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Jubilee Soup Kitchen, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - June 12th Rally, New York City, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 23-24)
    - Labor Struggles, 1999 (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Lenten Series, 1978, 1979, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 26-28)
    - Lenten Series, Non Violence, ca. 1973 (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Lenten Series Advent Booklets, 1978-1981 (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - Lenten Series Booklets, 1977-1984 (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - Libya Bombing Protest, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - Marianist Voluntary Service Communities, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - May Day Peace March, 1999 (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - May Day Stars of the 20th Century Essay Contest (Box 53, Folder 35-36)
    - May Day Stars of the 20th Century Essay Contest Winners (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - Military Issue: Star Wars, 2000-2001 (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - Military Spending in Pittsburgh, 1984, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - National Rainbow Coalition, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - National Rainbow Coalition First Biennial Convention, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - National Rainbow Coalition Labor Network, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 42)
    - National Youth Pro-Life Convention, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 43)
    - The New People, 1974-1983 (Box 53, Folder 44-55)
    - The New People, 1984-2008 (Box 54, Folder 1-29)
    - New Prison Construction Protest--Indiana, Pennsylvania, 1997 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Nuclear Abolition, 2000-2008 (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Onehood, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - Pastors for Peace, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Peace Development Fund, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 34)
    - Pittsburgh Area Chapter Stand for Children, 2000 (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Pittsburgh Area Pax Christi, 1998 (Box 54, Folder 36)
    - Pittsburgh Committee for a Comprehensive Peace in the Middle East, 1991 (Box 54, Folder 37)
    - Pittsburgh Foundation, 2003 (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - Pittsburgh Social Forum, 2002 (Box 54, Folder 39)
    - Pittsburgh Study: Black Infant Mortality, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 40)
    - Pittsburgh Volunteer Collaborative Pilot Program, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 41)
    - Pittsburghers Against Apartheid, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Racism, 1985, 1997-1998 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Raffle Licenses, 2006-2008 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Regional Retreat, Fifteen Peace Groups, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Renaissance Center, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Rock Against Racism, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Rock Against Racism, 2003 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - School of the Americas, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Stand for Children, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Stars for Justice, 2000 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Stars for Justice Responses, 2000 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Thomas Merton Celebration, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Three Rivers Network, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Treatment for a Film on Dorothy Day (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - United Way Day of Caring, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - University of Pittsburgh Hunger Strike, 1999 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - The Voice, 1976-1980 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Women's Rights Issues, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Working for Peace and Prosperity, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Youngstown Steel, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Audio/Visual, 1967-1997; 3.
    This subseries includes a collection of over 500 photographs documenting Center activities, from staff retreats to community protests. Twelve slideshows used by the Center deal with issues including war, labor and world hunger. Over 120 cassette tapes, sound reels and VHS tapes feature speakers of varying prominence, speaking on the issues of peace and social justice dealt with throughout the rest of the collection.
    - Images
      - All-Day Board/Staff Retreat, Thomas Merton Center (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Amos House, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Anthony Padovano Retreat, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - Anti-Death Penalty Rally in Philadelphia WPCADP, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - Association of Pittsburgh Priests Protest Nuclear Testing, Nevada Test Site (Box 56, Folder 14)
      - "Beyond Good Intentions," Anti-Racism Speaker Series, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 15)
      - Board/Staff Planning, October 5, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 16)
      - Christian Peacemakers Retreat, Kirkridge, 1992(?) (Box 56, Folder 17)
      - Citizens Budget Campaign, Paper Plate Campaign, Mothers Day, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 18)
      - City Council Hearing, Citizens Budget Campaign, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 19)
      - Close School of the Americas Protest in D.C., 1995 (Box 56, Folder 20)
      - Declaration of Life Anti-Death Penalty Rally, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 21)
      - Demonstration for Baghdad, Iraq Gulf War (Box 56, Folder 22)
      - East End Community Thrift Shop Fashion Show (Box 56, Folder 23)
      - Economic Concerns Meetings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 24)
      - End Blockade of Cuba Rally in DC (Box 56, Folder 25)
      - Events and Meetings, January 1991 (Box 56, Folder 26)
      - Free South Africa, Pittsburgh in Washington, June 1989 (Box 56, Folder 27)
      - Gang Peace Council (Box 56, Folder 28)
      - Guatemalan Speaking Tour, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 29)
      - Haiti Celebration, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 30)
      - Holiday Open House, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 31)
      - Hopital Sainte Croix, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 32)
      - International Exchange (Box 56, Folder 33)
      - Jim Douglass Retreat, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 34)
      - Jim Forest Retreat (Box 56, Folder 35)
      - Jim Wallis and Richard Rohr Retreat, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 36)
      - Kirkridge Christian Peacemakers Retreat, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 37)
      - Kita Exhibit, University of Pittsburgh, Frick Art Museum, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 38)
      - Merton Award, Dan Berrigan, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 39)
      - Merton Award, Howard Zinn, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 40)
      - Merton Award, Howard Zinn, Msgr Rice, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 41)
      - Merton Award, Joan Baez, Duquesne Union Ballroom, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 42)
      - Merton Award, Marian Wright Edelman, Children's Defense Fund, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 43)
      - Merton Award, Molly Rush, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 44)
      - Merton Award, Richard Rohr, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 45)
      - Merton Retreat, Mt. St. Macrina (Box 56, Folder 46)
      - Merton's Hermitage, Monastery at Gethsemani (Box 56, Folder 47)
      - Middle East Peace, Trinity Cathedral, January-April 1991 (Box 56, Folder 48)
      - Miscellaneous Friends and Events (Box 56, Folder 49)
      - New Person Award, John Townsend (anti-nuclear weapons) (Box 56, Folder 50)
      - New Person Award, Joni Rabinowitz and Joyce Rothermel, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 51)
      - New Person Award, Joni Rabinowitz and Joyce Rothermel, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 52)
      - Nica Embargo (Box 56, Folder 53)
      - Nicaragua (Box 56, Folder 54)
      - Nicaragua San Isidro (Box 56, Folder 55-56)
      - Nicaragua Witness for Peace (Box 56, Folder 57)
      - Open House, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 58)
      - People (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Phon-a-thon Fundraiser, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Pittsburgh City Council, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Pittsburgh Coalition for a Comphrehensive Peace in the Middle East, Gulf War Protest/Prayer Service (Box 57, Folder 4-5)
      - Pittsburgh North People for Peace, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - PPQ Quincentennial, Point Park Native Americans, 1991, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Pray and Resist, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Protest Murders in Central America, Four Nuns and Archbishop Oscar Romero (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - Protesting War in El Salvador, New Hope Brigades, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 10-11)
      - Protests (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Quest for Peace Cuba Rally in DC, November 1994 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - River City Campaign CD at Westinghouse HQ downtown Pittsburgh in Lobby, 1987 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - River City Campaign Protest SEI (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - River City Ribbon around W and Display at Friends' Meeting (Box 57, Folder 16-17)
      - Rodney King Demo in Pittsburgh, May 1992 (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - Sculptures, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Sister City, 1991 (Box 57, Folder 20)
      - Sister City Picnic at Home of Jane Dirks and Steve Heitle, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 21)
      - Sister City Pottery Show at Don Fisher's, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 22)
      - Sister City Send Off to San Isidro, 1991 (Box 57, Folder 23)
      - Stop Police Violence Protest (Box 57, Folder 24)
      - Thomas Merton Center Advocacy Training Workshop, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 25)
      - Thomas Merton Center Events, 1988-1991 (Box 57, Folder 26)
      - Thomas Merton Center Giving Tree (Box 57, Folder 27)
      - Thomas Merton Center Giving Tree, 1988-1989 (Box 57, Folder 28)
      - Thomas Merton Center Pancake Breakfast, St. Mary Laurenceville, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 29)
      - Thomas Merton Center Picnic, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 30)
      - Thomas Merton Center Square Dance (Box 57, Folder 31)
      - Thomas Merton Center Summer Picnic, Schenley Park, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 32)
      - Thomas Merton Center Swim Party, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 33)
      - Thrift Shop Holiday Open House, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 34)
      - Urban Plunge, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 35)
      - Vigil Against Wars in El Savador and Guatemala (Box 57, Folder 36)
      - Automated Air War, B-1 Bomber Rockwell Int'l, USS Pittsburgh "Not in Our Name" Rally Slideshow (Box 57, Folder 37)
      - The Dream of an Impenetrable Shield: Ballistic Missile Defense in the Nuclear Age Slideshow and Tape (Box 57, Folder 38)
      - El Salvador Labor Slide Show (Box 57, Folder 39)
      - "Guns or Butter?" Slideshow and Tape (Box 57, Folder 40-41)
      - "Hands on a Future" Slideshow (Box 57, Folder 42)
      - "I Have Heard the Cry of My People" Slideshow, Brazilian Bishops' Statement on Hunger, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 43)
      - "I Have Three Children of My Own" Slideshow, The Packard Manse Media Project, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 44)
      - "The Last Slide Show," The Packard Manse Media Project (Box 57, Folder 45)
      - Thomas Merton Center Slideshow (Box 57, Folder 46)
      - Thomas Merton Center Food First Slideshow/Filmstrip, ca. 1980 (Box 57, Folder 47)
      - Thomas Merton Center Hostage at Hell's Bottom the Economy and the Pentagon Slideshow, Packard Manse Media Project, April 1983 (Box 57, Folder 48)
      - "Under the Mushroom Cloud" Slideshow Script (Box 57, Folder 49)
    - Audio
      - Alice in Blunderland, 1982 (Box 58, Cassette 1)
      - Reverend Allan A. Boesak, Daily Worship Service, June 6, 1984 (Box 58, Cassette 2)
      - Father Bryan Hehir, For Justice Sake (Box 58, Cassette 3)
      - City of Peace, 2-4-1 (SUMMIT UP), 1985 (Box 58, Cassette 4)
      - Donahue and Rushdie, 20+ Writers (Box 58, Cassette 5)
      - Joe Holland, "Background of the Pastoral", May 30, 1975 (Box 58, Cassette 6)
      - John Hauchey, S.J., Justice and Life in Holy Spirit, 1975 (Box 58, Cassette 7)
      - Maureen Clark, CSJ, Prison Ministry, October 13, 1986 (Box 58, Cassette 8)
      - On Amnesty, Vietnam, 1973 (Box 58, Cassette 9)
      - Pax Christi Conference, 1973 (Box 58, Cassette 10)
      - Social Ministry in Church of Today and Tomorrow, Reverend Brian Hehir, 1979 (Box 58, Cassette 11)
      - "Talking Across Lines", 1995 (Box 58, Cassette 12)
      - Thomas Merton Center Slideshow (Box 58, Cassette 13)
      - Thomas Merton Center 10th Anniversary (Box 58, Cassette 14)
      - Troubadour of the Great King, John Michael Talbot (Box 58, Cassette 15)
      - Vasily Shumov, My District, 1989 (Box 58, Cassette 16)
      - Father Cyprian Davis, OSB, Black Spirituality in What We Have Seen and Heard, 1985 (Box 58, Cassette 17)
      - Greer Gordon, The Study Guide on the Black Bishops Pastoral, 1985 (Box 58, Cassette 18)
      - Father Joseph Brown, SJ, The Spiritual and Prophetic Voice of Black Literature, 1985 (Box 58, Cassette 19)
      - Art McDonald: American Catholicism and American Foreign Policy, October 1983 (Box 59, Cassette 20)
      - Dan Sheehan, Christic Institute on Contragate/Lawsuit, 1987 (Box 59, Cassette 21)
      - Ken Medema and Friends, El Dios Revelado, September 1986 (Box 59, Cassette 22)
      - Special Meeting on Chile, APHA, November 1973 (Box 59, Cassette 23)
      - U.S. Security and Central America, Robert W. White, 1988 (Box 59, Cassette 24)
      - Gar Alperovitz, "The Consumer's Response: An Economic Analysis", CCUM Fall Conference, 1979 (Box 59, Cassette 25)
      - Archbishop Marcus McGrath, "Economic Justice: A Global Religious Issue", CCUM Fall Conference, 1979 (Box 59, Cassette 26)
      - Al Fritsch, "Appalachia" (Box 59, Cassette 27)
      - Al Fritsch (Box 59, Cassette 28)
      - Holy Smoke: Biblical Reflections on the Energy Crisis, Packard Manse Media Project, 1980 (Box 59, Cassette 29)
      - Peter Timmerman, Sustainable Ethical Development of the Earth, Environmental Week (Box 59, Cassette 30)
      - Warren H. Lindner, Global Ethics, Environmental Week (Box 59, Cassette 31)
      - "The Vulnerability of Jesus" (Box 59, Cassette 32-34)
      - "The Cry of the Wounded" (Box 59, Cassette 35-37)
      - "Opening our Hearts to the Spirit" (Box 59, Cassette 38)
      - Public Talk at BLANCHET (Box 59, Cassette 39)
      - "Growing in Jesus" (Box 59, Cassette 40-42)
      - "Guns or Butter", SANE Slide Show (Box 60, Cassette 43)
      - Michael Klare, "Armsrace", Carlow College, November 16, 1984 (Box 60, Cassette 44)
      - National Council for A World Peace Tax Fund (Box 60, Cassette 45)
      - The National Security State, Gore Vidal, March 1988 (Box 60, Cassette 46)
      - Presbyterian Mennonite Shalom Conference, 1987 (Box 60, Cassette 47)
      - "Who's Ahead?: The Debate over Defense", CBS Reports, April 20, 1977 (Box 60, Cassette 48)
      - Anima Bose: Gandhian Nonviolence, 1984 (Box 60, Cassette 49)
      - Jim Wallis: Living the Disarmed Life (Box 60, Cassette 50)
      - Michael Johnson: Two Styles of Nonviolence M. Ghandi, M. King (Box 60, Cassette 51)
      - Peace Pilgrim (Box 60, Cassette 52)
      - Shelley Douglass, River City Campaign, 1986 (Box 60, Cassette 53)
      - Beyond War: An Economic Perspective, Dr. Gary Williams, 1985 (Box 60, Cassette 54)
      - Carl Sagan, Do We Have A Future?, 1987 (Box 60, Cassette 55)
      - Beyond War: Children in the Nuclear Age, Annette Bain, 1985 (Box 60, Cassette 56)
      - Days to Remember, Read by Marcy Murdock (Box 60, Cassette 57)
      - Gordon Cosby, "Where do we root our security?" (Box 60, Cassette 58)
      - Helen Cladicott, M.D., "I Have Three Children of My Own", 1979 (Box 60, Cassette 59)
      - Helen Cladicott, M.D., Individual Responsibility, NFPC Convocation, October 1983 (Box 60, Cassette 60)
      - Helen Cladicott, M.D., The Pastoral: Basis for individual Responsibility, October 25-28, 1983 (Box 60, Cassette 61)
      - Jim Douglass, Friend Meeting House, August 16, 1981 (Box 60, Cassette 62)
      - "John, Mary, MIRV & MaRV: The Arms Race & the Human Race", Operation Turning Point, 1979 (Box 60, Cassette 63)
      - "The Last Slideshow", 1978 (Box 60, Cassette 64)
      - Raymond Hunthausen, Finding Our Way Back: A Christian Response to Nuclear Weapons, 1982 (Box 60, Cassette 65)
      - Rich Hayden, Nuclear Power, January 11, 1978 (Box 60, Cassette 66)
      - Under the Mushroom Cloud, FAS Nuclear War Education Project (Box 60, Cassette 67)
      - Allowing God's Love to Reprogram Our Relationships (Box 61, Cassette 68)
      - Reverend Charles Gallagher, "The Family is Good News" (Box 61, Cassette 69)
      - Constance Cumby, The New Age Movement (Box 61, Cassette 70)
      - A Dialogue about Annulments (Box 61, Cassette 71)
      - Stephen Kelleher, "Divorce and Remarriage" (Box 61, Cassette 72)
      - Jeanie Wylie, Dealing with Surveillance (Box 61, Cassette 73)
      - Phillip Agee and the CIA (Box 61, Cassette 74-75)
      - Anthony Padovano, "The Inevitable Catholic", 1973 (Box 61, Cassette 76)
      - Jim Wallis, Community Pittsburgh, 1983 (Box 61, Cassette 78)
      - Henri Nouwen, February 2, 1985 (Box 61, Cassette 77)
      - Jim Wallis, The Desert, Prayer, and Resistance, September 1983 (Box 61, Cassette 79)
      - Reverend Matthew Fox, Developing American Prayerfulness for Today...For Tomorrow (Box 61, Cassette 80)
      - Richard Rohr, "Breathing Under Water" (Box 61, Cassette 81)
      - Sister Anne Carr, The Church in Progress: Engendering the Future, 1975 (Box 61, Cassette 82)
      - Sister Clarita Trujillo, Journey to Justice: A Call to Action and Liberation, 1977 (Box 61, Cassette 83)
      - Bishop Judith Craig, August 3, 1987 (Box 61, Cassette 84)
      - Sister Margaret Farley, The Moral Imperatives for the Ordination of Women, 1975 (Box 61, Cassette 85)
      - Sister Mary Daniel Turner and Sister Margorie Tuite, Possibility and Vision: Synthesis and Strategy, 1975 (Box 61, Cassette 86)
      - Sister Marie Augusta Neal, Models for Future Priesthood, 1975 (Box 61, Cassette 87-88)